<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-09-15T14:21:37+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ashish Moktan</title><subtitle>I am Ashish Moktan and currently doing internship from  SYF Nepal. I am pursuing my CSIT from Trinity College Nepal.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First Day of Ruby</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2019/10/09/First-Day-Of-Ruby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Day of Ruby" /><published>2019-10-09T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-10-09T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2019/10/09/First%20Day%20Of%20Ruby</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2019/10/09/First-Day-Of-Ruby/">&lt;p&gt;Ruby is a scripting language designed by Yukihiro Matsumoto, also known as Matz. It runs on a variety of platforms, such as Windows, Mac OS, and the various versions of UNIX. This tutorial gives a complete understanding on Ruby.
Ruby is a pure object-oriented programming language. It was created in 1993 by Yukihiro Matsumoto of Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the name Yukihiro Matsumoto on the Ruby mailing list at www.ruby-lang.org. Matsumoto is also known as Matz in the Ruby community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is “A Programmer’s Best Friend”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby has features that are similar to those of Smalltalk, Perl, and Python. Perl, Python, and Smalltalk are scripting languages. Smalltalk is a true object-oriented language. Ruby, like Smalltalk, is a perfect object-oriented language. Using Ruby syntax is much easier than using Smalltalk syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features of Ruby
Ruby is an open-source and is freely available on the Web, but it is subject to a license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is a general-purpose, interpreted programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is a true object-oriented programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is a server-side scripting language similar to Python and PERL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby can be used to write Common Gateway Interface (CGI) scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby can be embedded into Hypertext Markup Language (HTML).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby has a clean and easy syntax that allows a new developer to learn very quickly and easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby has similar syntax to that of many programming languages such as C++ and Perl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby is very much scalable and big programs written in Ruby are easily maintainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby can be used for developing Internet and intranet applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby can be installed in Windows and POSIX environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby support many GUI tools such as Tcl/Tk, GTK, and OpenGL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby can easily be connected to DB2, MySQL, Oracle, and Sybase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby has a rich set of built-in functions, which can be used directly into Ruby scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tools You Will Need
For performing the examples discussed in this tutorial, you will need a latest computer like Intel Core i3 or i5 with a minimum of 2GB of RAM (4GB of RAM recommended). You also will need the following software −&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux or Windows 95/98/2000/NT or Windows 7 operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apache 1.3.19-5 Web server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internet Explorer 5.0 or above Web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby 1.8.5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will provide the necessary skills to create GUI, networking, and Web applications using Ruby. It also will talk about extending and embedding Ruby applications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ashish Moktan</name></author><summary type="html">Ruby is a scripting language designed by Yukihiro Matsumoto, also known as Matz. It runs on a variety of platforms, such as Windows, Mac OS, and the various versions of UNIX. This tutorial gives a complete understanding on Ruby. Ruby is a pure object-oriented programming language. It was created in 1993 by Yukihiro Matsumoto of Japan.</summary></entry></feed>